<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<DOCSTREAM>

<DOC id="AUTOWEEK_909209996" type="story" >

<HEADLINE>
Renault F1 awaits fate on Monday, team's future unclear
</HEADLINE>

<DATELINE>
MIAOWANZHEN, China, Dec. 1
</DATELINE>

<TEXT>
<P>
Formula One's Renault crash saga should finally reach a conclusion in Paris on Monday when the FIA World Motor Sport Council (WMSC) conducts its hearing into Nelson Piquet Jr.'s accident in last year's Singapore Grand Prix.
</P>
<P>
The story has hogged the headlines since it first came to light three weeks ago today (Sept. 20).
</P>
<P>
Last week saw high drama as team principal Flavio Briatore and his technical boss and de facto deputy Pat Symonds both left the team, while Renault issued a statement to say that it will “not dispute” the allegations against it. Those allegations say that Briatore and Symonds asked Piquet to crash on purpose, thereby causing a safety-car period that helped teammate Fernando Alonso execute a bizarre pit-stop strategy to take the win.
</P>
<P>
Renault's apparent admission of guilt did not stop the hearing, but the meeting will now be more about the sentence rather than the FIA attempting to prove its case.
</P>
<P>
Just what type of sentence the WMSC will administer has been the subject of considerable speculation. Action against Briatore and Symonds is compromised by the fact that they left Renault. Unlike for drivers--who hold FIA-issued licenses--there is no clear procedure regarding how ex-employees can be banned from future involvement in motorsports.
</P>
<P>
Briatore is still likely to attend the hearing, while news emerged Sunday that the FIA has asked Alonso to also appear. The FIA appears to have absolved him from any knowledge of the plot, and he could be there to discuss his relationship with Briatore in more detail. Expect the FIA to take action that blocks team bosses from also managing drivers, a practice Briatore has engaged in for many years.
</P>
<P>
The WMSC might look favorably upon Renault's capitulation, but there is no question that FIA president Max Mosley takes the issue very seriously. Possible punishments could include exclusion from this year's championship, a heavy financial penalty and/or a draconian suspended sentence. Renault might have to send its cars and personnel home from Singapore prior to next weekend's race, should the team receive be a ban that affects this season.
</P>
<P>
Renault is awaiting its sentence before making a definitive decision about next season. Having already lost title sponsor ING, the team lacks outside financial support for 2010. Company boss Carlos Ghosn could decide to withdraw the team from F1 and attempt to sell it, just as Honda and BMW did this year.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
</DOCSTREAM>